Eden Cardim

IT Consultant March 3, 2016

PROFILE

I have been developing software and administering systems since 1998 and have collaborated with several open source projects. I also specialize in planning and developing both relational and big data database architectures with cloud computing.

I'm concerned with social awareness, equality and sustainability, most of my volunteer efforts are geared towards social improvement and climate change.

CONTACT

edencardim@gmail.com https://github.com/edenc +55 11 9 9644 8225

> Rua Almirante Brasil, 243 Ap. 132C Mooca, SP Brasil

SKILLS

SQL	Javascript	Perl
R	C++	С
Prolog	Haskell	Java
LISP	Ruby	Python
MySQL	PostgreSQL	L TEX
Git	Hadoop	Apache
Windows	FreeBSD	Linux

LANGUAGES native Portuguese

fluent English mostly reading Spanish

EDUCATION

Universidade Estadual de Santa Cruz Computer Science BSc.

PUBLICATIONS

The Definitive Guide to Catalyst - 2009

Kieren D., Matt T., Eden C., Jay K., Jess R. ISBN-13 978-1430223658 ISBN-10 1430223650

AWARDS & HONORS

Desarollando America Latina - 2011

Won the first edition of the Desarollando America Latina hackathon by implementing the *Onde Acontece* application, facing competition of 18 teams from countries across Latin

EXTRA-CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

Google Summer of Code - 2011

Voluntary mentor involving the improvement of Catalyst's dependency injection mechanism.

São Paulo Perl Workshop - 2011 Speaker FISL - 2008, 2009 Speaker CONISLI - 2008 Speaker

EXPERIENCE

Tata Consulting Services São Paulo, Brazil

BI Analyst Mar 2016-Present

IBM São Paulo, Brazil

Database Analyst Jul 2014-Mar 2016

Design database architectures for both big data and relational database systems. Demonstrate capacity to potential clients during the pre-sales phase then deliver and deploy solutions at the client site.

urby.com.br São Paulo, Brazil

Technical Director Jun 2013-Jul 2014

 $\label{lem:periodical} Design \ IT \ architecture \ and \ infrastructure \ solutions \ applied \ to \ geocomputation. \ Support \ development \ teams \ on \ design$ decisions. Hands-on development with Javascript, Perl, PostgreSQL and PostGIS.

Insolide IT São Paulo, Brazil

CTO Jun 2013-Jul 2014

Negotiate contracts with customers, project management and hands-on development with Perl, Ruby, PostgreSQL, Apache and Amazon Web Services.

Clients/Projects

Instituto Ruth Cardoso

Estante Virtual

Shadowcat Systems Ltd. Lancaster, UK

Lead Developer Jan 2008-Aug 2013

Database/Software design and implementation, project management and Catalyst/DBIx::Class scalability solutions for high-traffic websites. Built tailor-made Business Intelligence tools for customers.

Clients/Projects

University of Indiana

Cisco Systems Inc.

US Census

British Broadcasting Company

Takkle Inc.

Socialflow Inc.

IonZero LLC Fort Collins, USA

Software Developer Aug 2010-Dec 2010

OLAP solutions and operations for various customers.

DBIX Corp. San Francisco, USA

Software Developer Feb 2008-May 2008

Parsing/lexing solutions for domain-specific programming languages. Implemented a Wiki from the ground up to demonstrate DSL capacities.

Picture Trail Inc. Silicon Valley, USA

Software Developer Jun 2007-Dec 2007

Scalability solutions and software design for Catalyst-based web applications.

Núcleo de Biologia Computacional e Gestão de Informações Biotecnológicas

da Bahia Ilhéus, Brazil

Researcher Feb 2005-Aug 2007

Bioinformatics applied to research on the *Moniliophtbora roreri* genome. Designed and implemented genomics analysis tools, annotation and processing workflows.

Vapt Net Ipiaú, Brazil

Systems Administrator Jan 1998-Jan 1999

Linux administration and support. Development of the corporate ticket portal.